[{
       "question":"What is an RDBMS?" ,
       "choice1":"Database that stores data elements that are not linked" ,
       "choice2":"Database that accesses data elements that are not linked" ,
       "choice3": "Database that stores and allows access to data elemts that are linked",
       "choice4":"None of the mentioned" ,
       "answer":3

},
   {   
      "question":"The primary key is selected from the _______",
      "choice1":"Candidate keys",
      "choice2":"Composite keys",
      "choice3":"Determinants",
      "choice4": "Foreign keys",
      "answer":1
},
{
     "question":"Which of the following commands do we use to delete a relation(RDBMS) from a database?",
      "choice1":"drop table RDBMS",
      "choice2":"delete table RDBMS",
      "choice3":"delete from RDBMS",
      "choice4": "drop relation RDBMS",
      "answer":1
},
{
     "question":"What does the following query do?\n UPDATE student \n SET marks=marks*1.10;",
      "choice1":"It decreases the marks of all the students by 90%",
      "choice2":"It increases the marks of all the students by 10%",
      "choice3":"It is syntactically wrong",
      "choice4": "It increases the marks of all the students by 110%",
      "answer":2
},
{
    "question":"Which of the following is preserved in the execution of transactions in isolation?",
      "choice1":"Atomicity",
      "choice2":"Isolation",
      "choice3":"Consistency",
      "choice4": "Durability",
      "answer":3
},
{
    "question":"The database is alwys expected to satisfy which predicate?",
      "choice1":"Assertion",
      "choice2":"Mandate",
      "choice3":"Verify",
      "choice4": "None of the above",
      "answer":1
},
{
    "question":"What kind of joins is a default in SQL?" ,
       "choice1":"Outer" ,
       "choice2":"Self" ,
       "choice3": "Inner",
       "choice4":"None of the above" ,
       "answer":3
},
   {
     "question":"A relation is in the form if it is in BCNF and has no multivalued dependencies" ,
       "choice1":"Second normal form" ,
       "choice2":"Third normal form" ,
       "choice3": "Fourth normal form",
       "choice4":"Domain/Key normal form" ,
       "answer":3
},
 {
     "question":"Which of the following is the correct option for the given query?\n SELECT DISTINCT name FROM RDBMS \n WHERE ID IS NOT NULL;" ,
       "choice1":"The query gives all the possible RDBMS names where a finite value exists for ID" ,
       "choice2":"The query gives the RDBMS names where a finite value exists for ID and it excludes identical names" ,
       "choice3": "The query gives the names of the RDBMS that have a null ID and it also excludes identical names",
       "choice4":"The query is syntactically wrong" ,
       "answer":2
},
{
    "question":"For each sttribute of a relation, there is a set of permitted values, called the _______ of that attribute" ,
       "choice1":"Domain" ,
       "choice2":"Relation" ,
       "choice3": "Set",
       "choice4":"Schema" ,
       "answer":1
}]